Hey.
嘿
Dad.
老爸
What?
又怎麼了?
Showtime, baby doll.
該上場了 小寶貝
- She's on the move. - All right, let's go.
- 人要出場了 - 沒事了 走吧
Good luck! Don't mess up!
好走 別搞砸了
This way. Follow me.
這邊 跟我走
- Come on. - She's coming right now.
- 跟上 - 就快到了
All right, talent's on its way.
人要到了
- Oh! - You do that every night.
你每次都這樣
- Love you, Daddy. - I'm loving you right back, darling.
- 我愛你 老爸 - 我也愛你 寶貝
Don't forget it's your turn to do the dishes tonight.
記住今晚輪到你洗碗
I did them last night.
我昨晚洗過的
Don't give me no lip. You're the one that wanted the best of both worlds.
別討價還價 是你自己說要兩個世界多美好的
- Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! - Watch your head.
- 漢娜 漢娜 漢娜 - 小心頭
Here we go, everybody! Whoo!
大家好！
Hannah Montana - The Best of Both Worlds
孟漢娜 - 兩個世界多美好
Oh, yeah.
* 喔 耶 *
Come on.
* 來吧 *
You get the limo out front
* 天天高級轎車代步 *
Hottest styles, every shoe, every color
* 熱門款式衣服 每雙鞋子 每個顏色 *
Yeah, when you're famous it can be kinda fun
* 當個名人 是挺好玩的 *
It's really you but no one ever discovers
* 明明是你 別人卻都沒發現 *
In some ways you're just like all your friends
* 別人雖然都是你的朋友 *
But on stage you're a star
* 但在舞台上 你就是明星 *
You get the best of both worlds
* 兩個世界多美好 *
Chillin' out, take it slow
* 慢慢來 放輕鬆 *
Then you rock out the show
* 然後盡情表演 *
You get the best of both worlds
* 兩個世界多美好 *
Mix it all together and you know that
* 兩個混合起來 你就知道 *
You go to movie premiers
* 可以參加電影首映會 *
Hear your songs on the radio
* 你唱的歌曲 電台最主打 *
Livin' two lives is a little weird
* 有雙重身份 其實有點怪 *
But school's cool cuz nobody knows
* 但一樣上學 別人都不知道 *
Yeah, you get to be a small town girl
* 你雖然是個鄉村女孩 *
But big time when you play your guitar
* 但只要當你拿起吉他 *
You get the best of both worlds
* 兩個世界多美好 *
Chillin' out, take it slow
* 慢慢來 放輕鬆 *
Then you rock out the show
* 然後盡情表演 *
You get the best of both worlds
* 兩個世界多美好 *
Mix it all together and you know that
* 兩個混合起來 你就知道 *
It's the best of both...
* 兩個世界多... *
best of both...
* 世界多 世界多... *
best of both world
* 世界多美好 *
Cut! We'll fix that last bit in post.
停!後面一段再處理
That's a wrap, people.
收工了 各位
- Hannah, as always, fabulous. - Thank you.
- 漢娜 還是依然魅力四射 - 謝謝
No. It's OK. I'm sorry. I just had to meet you.
別緊張 對不起 我只是想要見你一面
I promised my girls I'd say hi to you for them.
我跟女兒們保證 要代她們向你問好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
They even wrote out some questions, if you have a second.
她們甚至準備了一串問題 如果你有時間的話
Oh, my gosh, this is such a thrill. Do you mind?
我的天啊 太激動了 你不介意吧
- Not at all. - Don't even think about it.
- 沒關係 - 想都不要想
- No, Vita. It's OK. - Nothing about this man is OK.
醜女貝蒂 第三季 北京時間10/10回歸 敬請關注 風軟字幕組出品
Hello, Oswald.
你好 奧斯瓦德
Hello, Vita. Looking lovely as ever.
你好維塔 還是一樣漂亮
Icky teeth, really? Isn't that beneath even you?
你那假牙還真惡? 哪敢和你比啊
Oswald Granger, chief sleaze of Bon Chic magazine,
奧斯瓦德格蘭奇 孟詩格雜誌 狗仔記者組長
Britain's most notorious tabloid.
英國最臭名昭著的八卦週刊
And we would love, with a capital "ove,"
我們非常希望 強調"希望"
to do a cover feature on the global phenomenon that is Hannah Montana.
以全球時尚潮流巨星 孟漢娜 為下一期封面主題
And by "feature" he means "career-ending expose. "
他口中的"主題"就指"明星生活大曝光"
"Country girl living her dreams beloved by millions," that's all we got.
"鄉下女孩實現夢想 萬眾矚目" 我們能說的就這些
That's all you're gonna get. Now get out.
你也只能挖到這些 你可以走了
Can't blame a bloke for trying.
我要是全力出擊 可別怪我
How could you even think we have something to hide?
憑什麼你一口咬定我們有瞞著什麼
- He didn't see anything, did he? - I don't think so.
- 他沒看到什麼吧 對吧 - 我認為沒有
Good. Hannah, honey,
好的 漢娜 寶貝
you can't talk to anyone unless I'm at your side.
不准跟陌生人說話 除非我在你旁邊
I'm your publicist. You need to concentrate on what you do best
我是你的公關 你要把注意力 集中在最擅長的地方
which is singing your scrappy little heart out.
放開嗓子 大聲地唱
Let me worry about everything else,
剩下的我來操心
like making sure your little secret stays a secret.
比如 讓你的小秘密不公佈於眾
Sometimes I wish I could be Hannah all the time.
有時候 我真希望可以 永遠成為漢娜
You and me both, kid.
我和你都想 孩子
Out of the way, you jackals. Step aside. Coming through.
別擋路 狗仔們 一邊閃 讓我們過去
That's right, don't touch the pop star. Move aside.
對了 別碰我們的巨星 靠邊站
...like making sure your little secret stays a secret.
比如不讓你的小秘密公佈於眾
Secret? What secret? Move your bum, you old cow.
秘密? 什麼秘密 屁股挪開 你這頭母牛
Talk to me, Ozzie, and don't disappoint.
說吧 奧奇 別讓我失望
- Apparently there's a secret. - Good. Because the cover's ready.
- 她似乎有一個秘密 - 好 正巧封面照定下來了
I just need the story to go with it.
我還需要一個故事
Find out that secret. She's the most popular teenager in the world.
挖出那個秘密 她可是全世界 青少年中最炙手可熱的明星
So I suggest you go out and find me every juicy,
我要你去給我找出 這個
sordid detail of Hannah Montana's outrageous, glamorous life.
光彩照人的孟漢娜 有什麼見不得人的醜事
All right. Line it up, people. We're going to choose new teams.
大家排好隊 我們要選新隊伍
Dead girl in the middle of the floor. Anybody?
有人死在這了 幫一下?
Fabulous news: Beyonce has double pneumonia.
勁爆消息：碧昂絲得了肺炎
Has to drop out of the New York Music Awards. You're in!
必須放棄紐約音樂獎 你入圍了
That is great. Not for Beyonce.
太棒了 不是說碧昂絲
I really should call. But, yes! I'm so excited!
我真應該致電慰問 但太棒了 我真激動
What am I gonna sing? What am I gonna wear?
唱哪首歌? 穿什麼?
Great minds. The car and the box are already outside,
問得好 車和化妝盒 已經在外面待命了
so Hannah has to do a major shop now.
所以你要做的是去商場血拼
Last chance. Come on.
最後機會 走吧
Miley? Hello? What about my birthday party?
麥莉 我的生日派對怎麼辦
Minor Hannah emergency. I'll be there, I promise.
漢娜的小小緊急事件 我會去的 我保證
Wasn't that fun?
難道不過癮嗎?
Yeah, but it feels weird having them give me stuff for free.
但是白白拿東西走人很不習慣
Please. Do you know what a well-placed photo of you shopping is worth?
拜託 知不知道一張你光臨本店 的照片值多少錢?
You're a star, an icon.
你是一個明星 無敵偶像
You look at it, touch it, wear it, and the whole world has to have it.
你看過的 摸過的 穿過的 全世界的人都搶著要
They owe it to you, Hannah. Name it and it's yours.
是店老闆欠你的 想要什麼開口就是
- Really? - I have so much to teach you.
- 真的? - 我要教你的太多了
If she doesn't hurry, you're going to miss your plane.
她不快點的話 飛機就要起飛了
Yeah, that's right, losers! I'm going to college! Tennessee Universi...
嘿 失敗者 我要去大學了 田納西州大...
- University. - Where is that girl?
- 大學 - 那孩子跑哪去了
- I can't decide. - Decide? No deciding. Too stressful.
- 難以抉擇 - 抉擇? 不要選了 太費神了
Take them all. We'll just add them to the pile. Girls.
全包了 我們才進的新貨 姐妹們
Ooh.
哇
Watches. I totally need a new watch.
手錶 完全有必要配一隻
Is that the time? I can't believe it.
這時間准嗎 真不敢相信
We got to go. Eleven messages. Jackson.
我們要走了 11條短信 傑克森
Lilly's present. Lilly... would totally love those shoes.
麗莉的禮物 她絕對喜歡這鞋
- She will so love these. - I'm sorry. I saw these first.
- 這雙她肯定會喜歡 - 不好意思 我先看上的
Can you wrap these for me?
能幫我把它包起來嗎
They're for my best friend. She's 16 today.
這是要送我最好的朋友的 她今天16歲
Funny, they're for my best friend, too.
很有趣 我也是要送好朋友的
My best friend is a six and a half.
我好朋友穿6.5號
Funny, my best friend's a six and a half, too.
很有趣 我好朋友也穿6.5號
Tyra Banks, that's our only pair.
泰拉班克斯女士 我們只有這一雙
- Not funny. Do you know who I am? - I know you know who I am.
- 不好笑了 你知道我是誰吧 - 我想你知道我是誰
- So? - So?
- 所以呢? - 所以呢?
- Give me that shoe. - Get away from me!
- 把鞋給我 - 給我滾開點
You know what? If you want it, jump for it. Jump for the shoe, Hannah.
如果你要的話 跳起來拿啊 用跳的呀 孟漢娜
Fine. Gimme!
好 給我
Got it!
拿到了
Yes! Yes!
太好了 太好了！
Give me my shoe, lady!
把鞋給我 小姐
She is so in trouble.
她這下有麻煩了
No, you didn't! Hannah Montana!
不 你不能 孟漢娜
- Yes! - I appreciate you helping me up,
- 成功 - 你能來扶我 我很感謝
but I don't appreciate you not helping me with this.
但我不爽的是你不幫我搶鞋
Relax? Are you kidding me? Have you met my dad?
放心? 你開玩笑吧 你見了我老爸了?
He is not gonna shake off me missing saying goodbye to Jackson.
要是不去送傑克森的話 他是 不會放過我的
Give us a smile. You look amazing.
笑一個 你看上去太漂亮了
Thank you. We got to go.
謝謝 我們得走了
Hey!
嘿
And I didn't even get the shoes. I am the worst friend in the world.
我也沒搶到鞋子 我真是世界上最爛的朋友
It's him.
是他
Oswald. Step on it!
奧斯瓦德 開快點
I cannot get out of the car looking like Miley,
我不能以麥莉的樣子走出車去
and I cannot show up at Lilly's party looking like Hannah.
但是也不能以漢娜的打扮 出現在麗莉的派對上
Where are you headed?
看你往哪裡跑
Hi! Thank you. Thank you.
謝謝 謝謝
Hey, Lilly. What's up?
嘿 麗莉 怎麼了?
We've talked about this party since we were, like, 12. Where...
我們一直在幻想這個派對 從12歲開始 你在...
- Hi! How are you? Where are you? - I'm almost there.
- 嗨 你好啊! 你在哪? - 快到了
She hung up on...
她掛我電話
Where are you? Everybody's waiting...
你在哪啊 大家都在等
- Sorry, wrong number! - Miley!
- 對不起 打錯了! - 麥莉
Two smoothies, please. Where's Miley? We haven't seen her.
兩杯混合果露 麥莉在哪?沒看到她
Just spoke with her. She'll be here any second.
打過電話了 她說一會就到
Rico, what's this hole at the top of the cake?
利克 蛋糕上的大洞是幹什麼的
It's a high-pressure electro-pneumatic solenoid on it.
上面有一個高壓電動螺旋圈
It's 150 pounds per square inch with a brass safety-check valve.
每平方英吋150磅衝擊力 帶有一個銅質安全閥
Then I just hit this button and bam! Sparklers go off,
只要我按下按鈕 砰一聲 四處飛濺
and a "happy birthday, Lilly" banner shoots out the top of the cake.
從蛋糕頂部就會有小旗子跳出來 上面寫著"生日快樂 麗莉"
Once again... Rico is a genius.
又一次證明 利克是個天才
Hold it! This is a private event. Guests only! What did I tell you? Stop!
打住 這是個私人聚會 只有嘉賓入內 聽到我說話了嗎
- Smile. - No pictures.
- 笑一個 - 不允許照相
That's what I call a Lilly... Wow.
這就是我命名的"麗莉式..."
It's Hannah Montana!
是孟漢娜
Is that Hannah Montana?
是那個孟漢娜嗎?
Guys, I'm only here... Wait!
大伙 我只是來...
Happy birthday to... I want to say happy birthday to my number one fan, Lilly.
我是來跟我的頭號粉絲--- 麗莉說生日快樂
She's over that way. She's over that way.
她就在那邊 她就在那邊
Happy birthday, Lilly. Happy birthday.
生日快樂 麗莉 生日快樂
I'm sorry. I had no choice. I'll make it up to you, I promise.
對不起 我也沒辦法 我會補償你的 我發誓
You will never, ever, ever make it up to me.
你不會 永遠不能補償我
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Sing, sing, sing, sing, sing.
唱 唱 唱 唱 唱
Crazy, Crazy, Crazy, Crazy, Crazy.
瘋狂 瘋狂 瘋狂 瘋狂
Uh, you guys know the words to Let's Get Crazy?
你們知道"一起瘋狂"的歌詞麼
All right, then, here we go!
開始羅
You ready? Here we go.
你們準備好了嗎
Hannah Montana - Let's Get Crazy
孟漢娜 - 一起瘋狂
# Life is just a party so come as you are
* 生活是一場派對 大家只管來參加 *
# Dress it up or dress it down Don't forget your guitar, yeah
* 不管有沒有精心打扮 千萬別忘了帶吉他 *
# Just be courageous 'Cause style's contagious
* 只需要勇敢一點 因為時尚會傳染 *
# Everyone can rock out like a superstar
* 搖身一變 你就是明星 *
# Let's get crazy Get up and dance
* 一起瘋狂 跳起來吧 *
# Take a swing, do your thing It's worth taking a chance
* 搖一搖擺一擺 機會一定要把握 *
# Let's get crazy
* 一起瘋狂 *
# Yeah, just kick up your heels
* 對了 踢掉高跟鞋 *
# Don't miss out Time to shout
* 對了 別忘了尖叫 *
# Always keeping it real Let's get crazy
* 保持熱情 一起瘋狂 *
# Crazy
* 一起瘋狂 *
Lilly! Lilly, we got cake!
麗莉 麗莉 還沒切蛋糕呢
Hold up. Wait. Birthday Girl, I have some questions.
等等 壽星 我有幾個問題
Is it true Hannah's really 43 years old? She lip syncs? Grew up in Nashville?
漢娜真的是43歲嗎? 她會對嘴嗎? 在納什維爾長大?
More like a cornfield in some place called Crowley Corners.
確切一點 應該是 克勞利坊的一片玉米地裡
Really? How do you spell "Crowley"?
是嗎?"Crowley"怎麼拼的
It's Lilly Truscott, everybody! Happy birthday.
聽著 麗莉特拉斯科特 祝你生日快樂
We got cake over there.
我們準備了蛋糕
Just like it sounds.
根據發音來拼
- Lilly! - Oliver? Quick!
- 麗莉 - 奧利弗? 快點
Light the cake. We're gonna stop Lilly from leaving.
點蠟燭 我們不能讓麗莉走了
Cake? No, I'm not ready yet!
蛋糕? 不 我還沒準備呢
Come on! We have cake!
別走 還有蛋糕呢
Sorry.
對不起
Lilly, please pick up.
麗莉 求你接電話
- Did you see this? - Yeah, I know. It's everywhere.
- 看到了嗎 - 我知道 各大報紙的頭條
Isn't it... horrible. Bad Hannah.
這難道不...可怕嗎 壞女孩漢娜
She and I need to have a little conversation.
我要和她好好談談
Now? But she's getting ready to go to New York.
現在? 可她要飛去紐約了
Didn't she tell you? There's an amazing opportunity.
她沒告訴你? 好機會來了
Yeah, I know about New York. I got CCed in an e-mail. Not happening.
我知道 收到了郵件通知 不許去
She and I are flying to Tennessee for her Grandma Ruby's birthday.
她要和我去田納西州參加 她奶奶露比的生日聚會
Didn't she tell you?
她沒告訴你?
A shoe fight! You got into a stinking shoe fight?
搶鞋大戰? 為一雙鞋大打出手?
In my defense, I totally saw those shoes first.
錯不在我 明明是我先看中的
This is absolutely, T-totally, without a doubt unacceptable.
這是絕對的 無容置疑的 不可容忍的事情
Which pretty much describes all of your behavior lately.
正好用來形容你最近的行為
Standing up your brother? Humiliating Lilly at her own party?
放你哥哥鴿子 在麗莉的派對上讓她難堪?
I know. I screwed up. I'm sorry, but I can't talk about this now.
我知道 搞砸了一切 我也抱歉 但現在不是談這個的時候
I got to go to New York. It's the music awards.
我要去紐約參加音樂大獎賽
Your grandmother's birthday doesn't matter?
你奶奶的生日就不重要了?
This is totally different and you know it.
這完全是兩碼事 你知道的
Now, Robby. Mr. Ray.
聽我說 羅比 羅先生
Father Montana, Hannah not going to New York is really not an option.
孩子他爸 要漢娜不去紐約絕對免談
- Her name is Miley. - Miley'll be back before she leaves.
- 她叫麥莉 - 我保證麥莉可以趕得回來
She's a superstar. I can get her a private jet if she wants.
她是個明星 她想要的話 我可以幫她弄一架私人飛機
Yes! I've always wanted one of those.
太棒了 我早就想要了
For gosh sakes.
我的老天爺
Fine. You win.
好 你們贏了
But you heard our superstar. She needs a jet.
但你聽到我們小明星說的了 她需要一架飛機
- Really? - I like your thinking.
- 可以嗎? - 你能這樣想 我喜歡
It will take some time to arrange,
需要時間來安排
but I'll go ahead to New York and set up the meet and greet.
我會先去紐約安排見面會的事宜
Ooh. Next time, you might want to demand a jet with a bigger bathroom.
下次一定要訂衛生間大點的飛機
Why in the heck you getting all Hannahed up?
你這麼就把漢娜的行頭穿上了
The Hannah steps off the plane photo op.
出艙亮相照
The balloons, the limos, the screaming fans.
氣球 豪華禮車 粉絲瘋狂尖叫
Like Vita says, "It's all about the publicity. "
就像維塔說的 "公眾形象勝過一切 "
Yeah. That Vita's just full of good advice.
對 維塔就是一個智囊團
Absolutely full of it.
絕對是滿肚子的鬼點子
Hello, New York!
你好 紐約!
Looks like your limo's here.
好像你的豪華禮車來了
Ain't she a beaut?
她不美嗎?
Yee doggies. Tennessee.
小兔崽子 這就是田納西
Dad, come on.
老爸 別這樣
Yeah, maybe I should've remembered Grandma's birthday.
是 我本應該記住奶奶生日的
- I did. - Jackson, not now.
- 我就記得 - 傑克森 不是現在
Dad! Please, Hannah Montana needs to be walking down the red carpet
爸 不到三個小時之後 孟漢娜
in New York in less than three hours.
應該風光踩在紐約的紅地毯上
Miley, all you ever wanted to do was sing.
孩子 你所追求的就是唱歌
Hannah let you do that and still have a normal life.
漢娜讓你做到了 但你仍然有普通的生活要過
That was the dream, remember?
這才是你的夢想 記得嗎
That's why we created her in the first place.
這就是我們為什麼一開始 製造了這樣一個偶像人物
I don't know what she's about anymore.
我現在都不知道她的含義所在了
- What are you saying? - I think we might be done.
- 你想說什麼 - 我想應該就此結束了
- You can't take Hannah away from me. - Really? Because that's what I'm doing.
- 你不能把漢娜從我身邊奪走 - 是嗎 這正是我現在要做的
No! Stop the truck. I'm not doing this. I want to go home.
不 把這卡車停下來 我不要這樣 我要回家
Stop the truck!
停車!
You are home. Look around you.
你到家了 看看周圍
Hannah means everything to me.
漢娜是我的一切
That right there might be the problem.
這個正是問題所在
You're saying I can never be Hannah again?
我再也不能變成漢娜了嗎?
Ask me again in two weeks.
兩星期以後再問我
Right now let's see if a country girl still exists.
現在讓我看看眼前的女孩 是否還是那個鄉村小姑娘
- Two weeks? - Think of it as a Hannah detox.
- 兩星期? - 把它當做漢娜戒除療程
Take that wig off and get back in the truck.
把假髮脫了 回到車裡來
No. I'm not getting back in the truck. No way.
我不進那卡車 絕不
I'm not getting back in the truck, Dad.
我不坐卡車回去 爸爸
I'm going to New York whether you like it or not, and I'm not... Whoa!
不管你喜不喜歡 我一定要 回紐約 我不要...噢
Give that back, you mangy little...
還給我 你這骯髒的小...
Look at that. Girl don't even recognize her own horse.
瞧瞧 這孩子連自己的馬都不認得
Now that truly is sad.
這真令人心涼啊
Blue Jeans?
藍牛仔?
Meet us at the house. Just about a mile up the road.
屋裡見 沿著這條路往下一英里
Don't forget your suitcase.
別忘了你的行李箱
In my defense, you do look different.
錯不在我 你確實馬大十八變了
Did you do something to your tail?
你給尾巴整容了?
Good boy. All right, now. Help me out.
好孩子 來 幫我一把
Hold still.
站著別動
Blue Jeans!
藍牛仔
Hi. You all right?
你還好吧?
Blue Jeans doesn't really take well to strangers.
藍牛仔很怕陌生人
Especially not dirty, sparkly ones.
特別對衣著整潔光亮照人的美女
I know. He's my horse.
我知道 他是我的馬
Miley?
麥莉?
It's me. Travis?
是我 特拉維斯
Travis Brody? We were in the first grade together.
特拉維斯布魯迪 我們一年級是同學
Me and you went to your Uncle Earl's farm and swam
我們倆去你叔叔厄爾農場玩 還有游泳
- and got poison oak all over our... - I remember you, OK?
- 結果被毒橡樹弄得全是... - 我記起你了 好吧
I also remember you hanging me headfirst down a well.
我還記得你把我頭朝下吊在井裡
Yeah. I guess I had a pretty big crush on you back then.
我其實從那以後就開始喜歡你
But don't worry about it.
別擔心
I'm over it.
早過去了
Good to know.
我很高興
Don't come around too often anymore, do you?
你現在不常回來 是吧
Often enough.
太久沒回來了
Only a couple times since your ma died that I've heard about.
你媽媽去世後只聽說過幾次你的消息
So how long are you staying?
這次打算呆多久?
- Two weeks. - Ha!
- 兩星期 - 哈
- Good luck with that. - What's that supposed to mean?
- 祝你好運 - 這是什麼意思
Considering what you're wearing
考慮到你的穿著
and the fact that you couldn't get back on your horse,
和你不能爬到自己的馬的馬背上
I'm guessing you went California on us.
我猜你是去了加州
I have not. You don't know anything about me or California.
我沒有 你對我和加州都一無所知
Let me guess, celebrities are just regular folk like you and me.
讓我猜猜 明星和我們這種 普通人沒兩樣
- Some are. - Oh. Uh-huh.
- 有些是 - 哦 額
You, uh... you actually know any?
你 認識他們?
I know Hannah Montana.
我認識 孟漢娜
Hannah Montana? Really?
孟漢娜 真的?
Yeah. I...
對 我...
I practically saved her life surfing the other day.
我前幾天衝浪的時候救過她的命
She owes me big time. We're like... We're like best friends.
她超級感激我 我們就像閨中密友
Huh. Best friends.
哈 閨中密友
They're all waiting for you inside. I'll take Blue Jeans, put him away.
他們都在裡面等你 我來照看藍牛仔 把它給我
- You don't have to do that. - It's kind of my job.
- 你不需要這麼做 - 這是我的工作
I've been working for your grandma for the summer.
我暑假一直在給你奶奶打工
Ooh.
喔
This is usually about the time someone would say "thank you. "
一般現在是對方說 "謝謝"的時候
- I was getting there. - No need.
- 我正要開口呢 - 免了
See you round, Smiley Miley.
回頭見 有活力的麥莉
Remember? That's what he used to call you. Smiley Miley.
記得嗎 他過去這樣叫你的
I remember.
我記得
I got my Miley back!
我的麥莉回來了
Come on, Miley, take the next verse.
來 麥莉 接下一段
Come on.
來吧
Get your dog back and your house back...
你的狗會回來 你的家會回來
I want my life back, Dad.
我想我的生活回來 爸爸
Sorry. Sorry, everybody. Hey.
對不起 對不起 大家
Happy birthday, Grandma.
生日快樂 奶奶
Well, I just blew out my candles, and I already got my birthday wish.
我正吹了蠟燭 許了生日願望
Come here, sweet thing. Ohhh.
過來 小甜心
I have missed you more than you can imagine.
我想死你了
And thank you.
謝謝
Thank you so much for this. I just love it.
謝謝送我這個 我太喜歡了
There's only one King,
世界上只有一個貓王
and I have been saving him a place of honor.
我為他一直留著這個榮譽之位
How long have you been planning this?
你準備這禮物花了多長時間
Must have taken you forever to find it.
肯定費了不少心血吧
Apparently, I've thought of nothing else for weeks.
顯然 這幾個星期就沒想過別的
Hurt your grandma's feelings
傷害奶奶的感情
and a chewed-up wig'll be the least of your worries.
一頂爛假髮  你沒有絲毫內疚
Hey, Uncle Chuck. Listen, it's time for cake.
查克舅舅 聽著 要切蛋糕了
I'll collect the supper plates, you pass out the forks.
我負責收盤子 你去發叉子
Give you a chance to say hi to a few folks.
給你個機會和親戚打聲招呼
- You remember Cousin Derrick. - What's with the rat?
- 記得表兄戴立科嗎 - 這老鼠是怎麼回事
Ferret. Harlow.
雪貂 叫哈羅
- Good to be home. - Yeah.
- 回家真好 - 對
Got any plates for me?
這有盤子要收嗎
Do me a favor. Introduce yourself to Lorelai over there.
幫我個忙 過去跟羅莉萊自我介紹
She's new and a little shy.
新來的還很害羞
You ain't up to your matchmaking again, are you?
你不是又重新當起媒婆來了吧
- Me? Never. - That's right.
- 我 怎麼可能 - 那就好
Then I reckon it would be a shame for anybody to feel left out.
主人絕不應該讓客人被晾在一旁
- Uh-huh. - Excuse me. Got anything for me?
不好意思 有盤子給我嗎
I don't know. Are you sure you can handle it?
我不知道 你一個人拿得下嗎
You'd be amazed at what I can handle.
你絕對會驚訝於我的能力
I don't believe we've met. I'm Robby Ray.
很榮幸見到你 我叫羅比雷
Told you you'd be amazed.
說過你會驚訝的
I got it. It's not that bad, ladies and gentlemen.
接到了 不是那麼糟 先生女士們
Oh, Lord!
天哪
- Howdy! - Oh, no.
- 你好! - 哦 不
Whee doggies! Great news, everybody.
我滴神啊 好消息 各位
Elvis is alive and well.
貓王仍然健在
I keep thinking I should change the wallpaper,
我一直想要換牆紙
but your mom picked this out when she was about your age.
但這是你媽 像你這麼大時自己選的
I like it.
我喜歡
You used to like a lot of things about coming to see me.
你曾經喜歡很多事情 好比 回來看我
- Grandma... - It's OK.
- 奶奶... - 沒關係的
I know it's not personal.
我知道不是針對我
- I just miss my Miley. - Why does everyone keep saying that?
- 我只是想我的麥莉了 - 為什麼每個人都這樣說
Maybe you should be asking yourself that question.
也許你該捫心自問一下
Caterpillar in a tree How you wonder who you'll be
樹枝上的毛毛蟲 可曾想過你是誰
Can't go far But you can always dream
不能瀟灑走四方 但是夢想無限大
Your daddy used to say that to you every night.
你爸爸過去每晚都會唱給你聽
Not so much anymore.
現在不唱了
Miley! Rise and shine!
麥莉 太陽曬屁股了
Commence Operation Save Hannah Montana.
行動開始 拯救孟漢娜
Morning! Sleep well? I've been up for hours.
早啊 睡得好嗎 我老早就起來了
How about I go feed the chickens and grab some eggs?
乾脆去餵喂雞 拿點蛋回來
Like I always say, ain't nothin' better than farm-fresh eggs for breakfast!
就像我說的 最美味的早餐 莫過於新鮮冒熱氣的雞蛋
Who in the Sam Heck was that?
那位傻氣的村姑是誰?
Here, chick-chick-chick-chick.
來啊 嘰嘰嘰嘰嘰嘰嘰
Get away from...
走開
How long you think before she figures out to put down the bucket?
她要多久才會想到應該放下桶子
Oh, I'm gonna...
我要...
All right. Here we go, one farm-fresh egg.
看看 一個新鮮雞蛋
- Y'all couldn't wait? - Darling, we waited,
- 你們等都不等我 - 親愛的 我們等了
but eventually we had to get on with the rest of our lives.
但是我們後半生還是要繼續
Get yourself cleaned up, honeybee. I'm taking you to the farmers' market.
回房收拾一下 小蜜蜂 我要帶你去農貿集市
Oh, Robby Ray, my gutters need fixing.
羅比雷 我的排水溝要人修
And my truck is making a noise you just don't want to hear.
還有卡車聲音太吵了 你壓根聽不下去
I'm on it.
我想辦法
If you need any help, talk to the foreman.
如果要人幫忙 去找工頭
Might be down by the vegetable patch.
可能在菜園那邊
Gotcha.
收到
But don't go squashing my squashes. They're prizewinners.
離我的南瓜遠點 它們可是得過獎的
Looks like you beat me to it.
看起來你搶先一步
Lorelai?
羅莉萊?
Uh, Ruby didn't... You're the foreman?
露比沒說... 你就是工頭?
- That would be me. - So that means you're living here, too?
- 工頭就是我 - 也就是說你也住這附近?
You're good at this.
你很會猜嘛
That's me, right over there.
那是我家 就在那邊
I was looking for a fresh start, and I guess Ruby thought
我想有個新的開始 露比說我和農場
that both me and the farm could use some looking after, so...
可以各取所需 所以
She does like putting things together, that's for sure.
她喜歡把東西都攪和在一塊 毫無疑問
Lorelai. The foreman.
羅莉萊 工頭
I'll be dang.
這回好玩了
All right, you guys.
好了 孩子們
I'd like to introduce you all to Tammy Wynette.
讓我給你們隆重介紹 泰咪溫斯特(美國鄉村歌手)
She is the fastest two-legged animal in the world.
她是世界上兩條腿中跑的最快的
She can't fly, she can't swim, but she sure can...
不能飛 不能游泳 但是可以...
...bite. Be careful.
咬人 小心點
We talked about this. Unless you want to see ostrich burgers
我們說好了的 除非你想讓快餐店菜單裡
on the menu at the snack bar...
出現鴕鳥漢堡包
I'll take it from here. Go feed Miss Pearl.
我來接手 去餵珍珠小姐
No, I hate Miss Pearl.
不 我討厭珍珠小姐
All right, kids. Who wants to see a real live...
孩子們 有誰想見見生龍活虎的
...alligator?
...鱷魚
Help!
救命!
Ah!
啊
What's with the giant udder?
那個母牛大乳頭是什麼意思
That is something you don't see in Beverly Hills.
這在比弗利山莊 可看不見
Old Man Crowley died and left the town the meadows,
老克羅雷去世了 留下鎮上的牧場
pretty much everything you can see.
現在幾乎所有你看得到的
But we don't exactly have enough for the taxes,
但是我們沒錢繳稅
so I've been helping organize a fundraiser or two.
我已經在組織資金籌備會
It's just awful. Developers circling like vultures.
太可怕了 開發商就像盤旋的禿鷹
Talking about putting up apartment buildings. Shopping malls.
伺機談論什麼建公寓樓 購物中心
A mall? Really?
購物中心 真的?
If they have their way, there won't be any open land left.
如果他們真的得逞 就不會有空地了
Hey, Ruby. How'd you like one of those, young lady?
露比 喜歡這些嗎 年輕小姐
- Thank you. - Come on, Miley.
- 謝謝 - 走吧 麥莉
- Would there be a Bloomie's? - We've got work to do.
- 有布魯明嗎(美著名百貨連鎖) - 我們還有事要做
Sorry.
對不起
- You're looking at the future. - Thank you.
- 這就是我們的未來 - 謝謝
I swear, everything about that man irks me.
我發誓 那個男人的一切都讓我噁心
- Morning, Miss Ruby. - Morning.
- 早 露比女士 - 早
See you got your granddaughter with you.
孫女也一起來了啊
- Yeah, sure do. - Ain't she grown some.
- 這個當然 - 是不是長高點了
Amazing what a little food and water will do.
給點乾糧 喂點水 就有這種效果
Nice chatting.
和您聊天很愉快
When we finish, maybe you and I can do a little shopping.
我們幹完後去買點東西
In there? No, thanks. I'm good.
這裡?不必了 我沒什麼需要的
Look, missy. You may be Hannah Montana back home,
小姐 你回去是孟漢娜
but here we're britches and boots. And...
但在這裡 我們就是鄉村牛仔
...if that ain't good enough for you, maybe you should just pack up and git.
如果你不滿意的話 大可以收拾行李走人
You might be fooling your daddy, but you sure as heck ain't fooling me.
你或許可以騙騙你爸爸 但休想騙得了我
Now, I'm sorry for fussing at you,
抱歉說話說得重了點
but... I just think you should consider yourself lucky that,
但 我只是想讓你覺得慶幸
for the time being, you have a place like this to call home.
一直以來 你有個叫家的地方
I do.
我知道
And I'm sorry.
對不起
I know you are.
我明白的
Come on!
來吧
- Right here? - Yeah.
- 在這? - 對
Now... slice up this watermelon for samples.
把這個西瓜切開當試吃品
You're looking at the future of Crowley Meadows.
你們看的正是未來的克勞雷牧場
I'm going to take this mood of mine and put it to good use.
趁剛才的火還沒消 過去發揮一下
Free samples! Here you go, girls.
免費試吃 來一塊 小姐
Ruby, you can have as many fundraisers as you want,
露比 你可以盡情去籌款
but you are not going to stop progress.
但是你阻擋不了歷史的進步
Turning Mills Pond into a landfill is not what I call progress.
把磨坊池塘變成垃圾場 我不覺得是進步
Well, obviously...
很明顯...
I'll be right back.
一會就回來
- Morning. - Morning.
- 早 - 早
Um, do you know this girl?
認識這個女孩嗎
Sure, Hannah Montana. I don't live under a rock.
當然阿 是孟漢娜 我又不是山頂洞人
No, obviously not. No, no.
不 當然不是
- You wanna try something? - A bit of that.
- 要來試點嗎 - 那個來一點
OK.
好的
That's very nice. That's delicious.
很美味 很好
- Uh, I'll be right back. - Maybe she used a different name.
- 我一會就回來 - 也許她用了其他的名字
- I don't think so. - Somebody must know where she lives.
- 我不這樣認為 - 有人肯定知道她住哪
- No. I got to go. - OK. Thank you!
- 我必須離開一下 - 謝謝
- Miley, help me get this... - Get up.
- 麥莉 過來幫這位... - 起來
Help him up now. Let's get him out of here.
拉他起來 快點離開這裡
Help me with this poor man. Are you OK?
幫助一下這位可憐先生 你沒事吧
- I'm terribly, terribly sorry. - Honey, you are so forgiven.
- 我真的 真的 萬分抱歉 - 別在意 親愛的 你太有才了
You're too kind. No, really.
你們太好了 不 我說真的
You're about the same age. You know this Hannah Montana?
你也是差不多大的 認識孟漢娜嗎
Hannah Montana! Who don't know Hannah Montana? She's famous.
孟漢娜!無人不知無人不曉 人家可是明星
She's telling everyone she's from this little patch of nowhere,
她對外公佈來自一個無名小鎮
but no one's ever seen her.
但這沒人見過她本人
I seen her, saw her, know her, knew her.
我見過 過去看過 知道他 過去知道
- You're the first one. - I know all the Montanas-es.
- 你是第一個說這話的 - 我手上有她所有的情報
Do you know where I could find them?
知道我能在哪裡找到她嗎
Sure. You go about five miles south of town, turn right at the first crick.
出城往南5英里 第一個路口往右轉
- Left at the second crook. - There you are.
- 第二個路口左轉 - 到達目的地
- There you are. - Oh.
- 到達目的地 - 噢
- So thank you. Thank you. - Yeah. Sure.
- 多謝 多謝 - 沒關係
- Take care. - Yeah. Thank you.
- 保重 - 謝謝你們
Hello?
有人嗎
Hello, anybody home?
有人在家嗎
- What? - A better question would be "where?"
- 什麼 - 我應該問"在哪"
As in "where's my story?"
例如"我的故事在哪"
Sorry, love. Two seconds.
對不起 等一下
- Hello? - Daddy, where are you? You didn't call.
- 你好 - 老爸 你在哪 沒給我們打電話
Sorry, darlings. Daddy's working. I'll call you back in two seconds.
寶貝們 爸爸在工作 一會再打給你們啊
Hurry. It's nearly lights out.
快點 要熄燈了
Sorry, Lucinda. Don't worry. I guarantee this Hannah Montana story is...
露辛達 不好意思 我保證 這一期孟漢娜的報道會...
Hannah Montana!
孟漢娜
I can't believe it! Dad! I'm glad we called you.
太不敢相信了 老爸 幸好我們有打給你
I don't believe this! Have you met her yet?
我真不敢相信 你見到她人了嗎
Not now, girls!
還沒有 女孩們
- Please get us her autograph! - I'm going to faint!
- 幫我們弄張簽名 - 我要暈過去了
Who's that? What's all that screaming?
誰在那 誰在鬼喊鬼叫的
- Darlings, I'll call you back. - Daddy, Daddy, make sure you do!
- 寶貝們 我一會再打來 - 爸爸 爸爸 你要記得啊
- Sorry. You were saying? - Ozzie, I want the dirt!
- 不好意思 你說到哪了? - 奧齊 我要一點骯髒的內幕
Trust me, I'm all over it.
相信我 我已經夠骯髒了
Oh, I messed up. Um...
彈錯了
Um, I'm sorry. Don't stop. I'm going.
我錯了 別停 這就走
Don't worry about it. I was goofing off.
別擔心 只是偷懶而已
I think it's great you're still doing that singing thing.
很高興你還在唱歌
Singing thing? What singing thing?
唱歌 什麼唱歌
Come on. Everyone knows that's all you ever wanted to do.
每個人都知道這是你夢寐以求的
And... you actually got a nice voice.
你確實有一副好嗓子
Thanks. I've heard that.
謝了 有人說過了
What did you think of the song? I wrote it.
你覺得剛才那歌怎麼樣 我寫的
- Song? - Yeah, that thing I was just singing?
- 歌 - 對 我剛才哼的那首
Did I mention I wrote it?
我沒有說是原創的?
And it seems like you got most of the notes right. So way to go, Miley.
大部分的音符都對了 繼續努力 麥莉
"Most"?
"大部分"?
- So why didn't you like it? - Jeez, I didn't say I didn't like it.
- 為什麼不喜歡 - 我可沒有說不喜歡
You sure didn't say you did.
你口頭沒說 心裡有說
- It's not bad. It just wasn't... - Good.
- 是不賴 只是不夠... - 好
About anything.
沒有內容
Doesn't tell me anything about who you are or what you feel.
沒有傳遞給我任何東西 你的內心所想所感
- You know what I'm feeling now? - I've got an idea.
- 現在知道我內心所想嗎 - 我猜得到
And sorry, but you asked.
對不起 但你要我說的
Why are you bothering with this anyway?
你在這搬來搬去打算幹什麼
Starting up an egg business. Me and Ruby struck a deal.
雞蛋養殖 露比和我談好了
I rebuild the coop, I get to sell the eggs.
我重建雞捨 生下來的蛋可以自己賣
It's a lot of rebuilding.
那你的工程就夠大的
Hey, you got to start somewhere, right?
總要有個起步 對吧
Life's a climb, but the view is great.
生活就像攀登 沿途風景無限
That's all you want to do, is sell eggs in Crowley Corners?
這就是你的夢想 在克勞雷賣雞蛋?
- Where else am I going to? - That's not what I meant.
- 我還能去哪 - 我不是這個意思
I know what you meant. You don't get this place, do you?
我知道你想說什麼 你不喜歡這裡 是吧
- Come on. Saddle up. - Where are we going?
- 把鞍裝上 - 我們要去哪
To show you... what you're missing.
帶你看看 你遺失的美好
- You're next! - No way! No!
- 輪到你了 - 沒門 不
Yes! We got it!
我們成功了
It's cold!
這太冷了
We should get going. We don't want to be late for the fundraiser.
走吧 要不然募集會要遲到了
Whoo-hoo! Good job, Daddy!
唱的太棒了 老爸
Robby Ray Stewart, everybody. Good to have you back, sir.
羅比雷 斯圖爾特 歡迎回來
- You were so great up there. - Thank you, honey.
- 你台上太帥了 - 謝謝 親愛的
What is the matter with him? He's dated before.
他怎麼了 又不是沒約會過
Maybe it's starting to mean something again.
也許要開始認真對待
We're going to slow it down for this next song, if that's all right.
讓我們平復一下心情 準備聽下一首 （國民小公主 泰勒絲）
- What? - She likes you. You like her.
- 想說什麼 - 她喜歡你 你喜歡他
Why do you have to make everything so complicated?
把事情搞得這麼複雜幹嘛
Miley, you just wouldn't unders...
麥莉 你不會明白
- How do you know she likes me? - Because she'd be crazy if she didn't.
- 你怎麼知道她喜歡我 - 要是不是 那她就是瘋子
You got a good point there.
說的有道理
I saw Lorelai go out back. Maybe you can go help her with the empties.
我看到羅莉萊去後面了 也許你應該去幫幫忙
I could try.
我盡量
Miley? Would you like to dance?
麥莉 有幸跳一曲嗎?
Sorry about that back there.
剛剛很抱歉
This trip was always supposed to be about Miley. Not really about me.
這次放假是為了麥莉的事 從沒想過自己
Ever think the two might be related?
從沒想過開展一段戀情
You're right. Our family's closer than most, more...
對 我們一家關係非常融洽 更加的
Secretive? I've noticed.
神秘?我覺察到了
So how's she doing?
她怎麼樣了
I have a feeling she...
我有種感覺 她...
We are gonna be just fine.
我們都會很好
Thank you.
謝謝
Miley, it's open mike night. You should give it a try.
麥莉 今晚是即興表演 你也來秀一下
No. Wait. It's good. I mean, my dad...
不 好是好 但是 我爸爸
- Come on. It's all about having fun. - No. No.
- 來吧 大家開心而已 - 不 不
- Travis! - Looks like we got ourselves a taker.
- 特拉維斯! - 我們今天來了個表演者
All right, um...
好吧
If you guys don't mind, I'm gonna add a little hip-hop to this hoedown.
不介意的話 我想在土風舞步中 融入街舞元素
All right, banjo, I'm gonna need you to come on up here.
五絃琴 我需要你們上台伴奏
And where are my girls at? Come on up.
我的女孩們呢 上前來
All right. Here we go.
好了 開始羅
Miley Cyrus - Hoedown Throwdown
麥莉希拉 - 來跳舞吧
# Everybody, come on off your seats
大家都給我站起來呀
# I'm gonna tell you about a beat that's gonna make you move your feet
* 我要教你們一種舞步 會讓你們動動腳趾頭 *
# If you're five or 82 this is something you can do
* 不管你是5歲還是82 你絕對能夠跳得好 *
# Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
* 左提 右夾 手指點點 鄉村風格加嘻哈 *
# Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
* 老鷹張翅放胸前 左右來回晃一晃 *
# Jump to the left, stick it, glide
* 跳到左邊 穩住 滑 *
You got it. Come on. OK, one more time.
學會了嗎 再來一遍
# Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
* 左提 右夾 手指點點 鄉村風格加嘻哈 *
# Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
* 老鷹張翅放胸前 左右來回晃一晃 *
# Jump to the left, stick it, glide
* 跳到左邊 穩住 滑 *
# Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
* 地上劃出一個Z 斜線腳尖不離地 *
# When the drum hits, hands on your hips
* 當鼓聲響起 雙手放腰間 *
# One-footed 180 twist and then a zigzag, step, slide
* 單腳轉過180° Z字步 跨 滑 *
# Lean it left, clap three times
* 左甩頭 拍三下 *
# Shake it out head to toe, throw it all together, that's how we roll
* 從頭到腳我最搖擺 加在一起 就是這樣 *
- # Do the hoedown - # Hoedown
- 來跳舞吧 - 來跳舞吧
# Throw it all together That's how we roll
* 加在一起 就是這樣 *
Come on. Here we go.
大家一起來
# Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
* 地上劃出一個Z 斜線腳尖不離地 *
# When the drum hits, hands on your hips
* 當鼓聲響起 雙手放腰間 *
# One-footed 180 twist and then a zigzag, step, slide
* 單腳轉過180° Z字步 跨 滑 *
# Lean it left, clap three times
* 左甩頭 拍三下 *
# Shake it out head to toe, throw it all together, that's how we roll
* 從頭到腳我最搖擺 加在一起 就是這樣 *
- # Do the hoedown - # Throwdown
- 來跳舞吧 - 來跳舞吧
# Throw it all together That's how we roll
* 加在一起 就是這樣 *
# Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
* 左提 右夾 手指點點 鄉村風格加嘻哈 *
# Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
* 老鷹張翅放胸前 左右來回晃一晃 *
# Jump to the left, stick it, glide
* 跳到左邊 穩住 滑 *
# Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
* 地上劃出一個Z 斜線腳尖不離地 *
# When the drum hits, hands on your hips
* 當鼓聲響起 雙手放腰間 *
# One-footed 180 twist
* 單腳轉過180°  *
# And then a zigzag step, slide lean it left, clap three times
* Z字步 跨 滑 左甩頭 拍三下 *
# Shake it out head to toe
* 從頭到腳我最搖擺 *
# Throw it all together That's how we roll
* 加在一起 就是這樣 *
- # Do the hoedown - # Throwdown
- 來跳舞吧 - 來跳舞吧
Our very own Miley Stewart, people.
我們大家的 麥莉斯圖爾特
You got a lot of nerve coming in here.
你居然還有膽子來
I'm sorry. I thought this was a community event.
不好意思 我以為這是個社區集會
Community. You wouldn't even know what that word means.
社區 你腦裡有這詞的概念嗎
Well, I know that your idea of it is a thing of the past.
我想你們的觀點只存在於舊時代
How much y'all raise tonight?
你們今晚募集了多少
A thousand dollars?
1000美元?
Two thousand dollars?
2000美元?
Whatever it is, I'll double it.
你們給個數 我出雙倍
We don't want your money.
我們不要你的臭錢
At the end of the day it ain't gonna matter.
今天就要過完了 你們這樣無濟於事
You can have a hundred of these, you ain't gonna raise the money
你們可以來100次 但是不可能籌夠錢
it's gonna take to save the Meadows,
要救牧場就需要奇跡
not unless The Beatles show up for a benefit concert.
除非披頭士過來辦一場慈善演出
Oh, wait. Small problem.
等等 小問題嘛
The sooner y'all accept the inevitable, the sooner we...
你們遲早要妥協的 我們越早...
Miley knows Hannah Montana.
麥莉認識孟漢娜
- Who's that? - She saved her life surfing.
- 誰在說話 - 她衝浪時救了她
They're best friends. She could help us out, right?
她們是閨中密友 她可以幫我們
Throw a concert. That would raise a ton of money.
開一個演唱會 可以募集到數不完的錢
Yeah! Yeah! Do it. Yeah. Call her.
對 就這樣 對 打給她
I guess I could give her a call.
我要不給她打個電話?
Hannah Montana knows Miley?
孟漢娜認識麥莉?
Oh, my gosh! It's Hannah Montana! I love you, Hannah!
老天爺 是孟漢娜 我愛你
Oh, my gosh. She's here. I didn't think she'd actually come.
她來了 我真的沒想過她能來
Thank you! Thank you, thank you, thank you. Give me a hug. Thank you.
謝謝 謝謝 謝謝來抱一個 謝謝
So rustic.
太...鄉村了
- I love it, Miley. - Thanks.
- 我喜歡 麥莉 - 謝了
This whole "pop star saves hometown" angle is genius.
這個 "巨星拯救家鄉"的點子 簡直是個天才
Not so genius that I forgive you for ditching me in New York
但是休想讓我原諒你 把我一個人撇在紐約
and almost costing me my job, but genius nevertheless.
差點丟了工作 無論如何 你還是個天才
So you must be Granny.
你肯定是奶奶了
Adorable. Oh, look at this place.
可愛極了 看這地方
It's just so, um... And, uh...
太 ... 多麼的...額
- It always smell like this? - Pretty much.
- 一直都是這個味道? - 基本上是
Excuse me.
借過
I am so sorry. You are the best friend I have ever had.
我很抱歉 你是我最好的朋友
When I thought you weren't gonna talk to me,
原本以為你不會跟我說話了
- that I might lose you forever... - Couldn't lose me if you wanted to.
- 我可能永遠失去你了 - 只要你不想休想甩掉我
Good, because I don't want to.
太好了 因為我可不想
And... sorry about talking to that reporter guy.
我也對不住你 跟那個記者亂說
What? Lilly, you're the one that talked to the reporter? How could you?
什麼 是你告訴記者的?為什麼
I thought this was one of those "you're sorry, I'm sorry" moments.
現在不是"互相道歉時刻"嗎
It is, and I am. And I swear Hannah'll never come between us again.
我是很愧疚的 我保證漢娜不會 出現在我們之間了
OK.
好的
- Miley? - Yeah?
- 麥莉? - 在
Could I come in and talk to you and Hannah?
我能進來 和你跟漢娜聊兩句嗎
- You be Hannah. - No, you're Hannah.
- 你當漢娜 - 不 你才是
- I can't. No, you be Hannah. Stop it. - Miley?
- 我不能 你來當 別吵了 - 麥莉?
It's kind of important.
這是很重要的事
- No. - Back.
- 不 - 後面
Stop doing this.
不要這樣
Stop!
停下
Come in.
進來
I'm so sorry. I didn't realize...
很抱歉 我不知道
No worries. This is just a little de-stressing.
別擔心 放鬆療法罷了
It helps with Hannah's jet lag.
有助於時差
Jet lag? But California's only two hours...
時差? 但加州到這才兩小時
Yes. But Hannah only flies west to east,
對 但她只從西邊往東邊飛
so... she gains time. She sometimes has to go
這樣她就賺到了時間 有的時候
the long way around. She's actually getting younger.
她要故意繞遠路飛 實際上她在變年輕
- Did you want something? - Uh, yeah.
- 你有話說? - 哦 是的
Hi, Hannah.
嗨 漢娜
I'm Lorelai. And we are just all so grateful that you're here.
我叫羅莉萊 你能來 我們太感激了
Foot massage.
足底按摩
Very L.A.
洛杉磯風格
- Miley, you up there? - He doesn't know.
- 麥莉 你在上面嗎 - 他不知道
That Hannah's here. He is going to be so excited.
漢娜在這 他肯定會興奮的
- Let me tell him. - I'll take over.
- 我去告訴他 - 那我來接手吧
No. Hannah considers me her personal, you know...
不 漢娜當我是私人  知道嗎
There's these things that... Fine.
有些事情需要  你來
Hey, but no talking.
但是 不許說話
So the mayor wants to throw this big bash in your honor this evening.
市長為了給你接風準備舉辦盛宴
And I've had lobsters flown in and everything just for you.
我已經訂了龍蝦空運過來 全都是為你準備好了
I hope they don't get too jet-lagged.
我希望它們不會也有時差
Anyway...
總之
Dad!
老爸
- Dad, what are you doing? - Fixing your grandma's gutter.
- 你在做什麼 - 修你奶奶的排水槽
Hold the ladder for me. And don't squish the squashes.
幫我扶梯子 別踩爛了南瓜
Please come down. It's an emergency. I need you now.
先下來 有急事 我需要你
- Is that a yes? - Mm-hm.
- 你同意了?
Oh! Oh, that's fantastic. Wow.
哦 這太好了
What is Lorelai doing rubbing Hannah's feet?
羅莉萊為什麼在按漢娜的腳
- Technically, they're Lilly's. - Stay.
- 準確來說 那是麗莉的 - 別動
Dad. Dad, we're all set. I talked to Derrick, and...
爸 我們準備好了 跟戴立科說過了
- What's with him? - Shh. Come here.
- 他怎麼了 - 噓 過來
Hey. Lorelai.
嘿 羅莉萊
- Why don't you let Hannah rest... - Shh, I think she's asleep.
- 為何不讓漢娜休息一下 - 噓 她應該睡著了
Poor thing. Jet lag.
可憐 時差
She only flies west to east.
她只從西往東飛
What? That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard in my life.
什麼 這是我這輩子聽到最雷人的說法
Some kind of celebrity thing.
某種明星病
But she said yes. She's coming to the mayor's dinner.
但她同意了 她會出席市長的晚宴
It was my job to get her there, and she is coming.
我只負責邀請她出席 她也同意了
- Great. - You're going, right?
- 太好了 - 你會來的吧
I don't know.
不知道
Is this you asking?
你是在邀請我嗎
Yeah. I think it might be.
對 我想是
Then this is me accepting.
那 我想我接受
- I think they're gonna kiss. - Yes!
- 他們要接吻了 - 太棒了!
Go, Daddy! Go, Daddy!
加油 老爸 加油 老爸
Certainly is getting hot in here. I think I'll open up the window.
怎麼熱起來了 我去開窗戶
I don't want her to sleep in a stuffy room.
我不希望她睡在悶熱的房裡
Daddy, Daddy.
老爸 老爸
Oh, Jackson!
哦 傑克森
Are you OK? Watch it. Ladder.
沒事吧 小心梯子
Are you all right? Let me help you.
你還好吧 我來幫你
I'm OK. I'm OK.
很好 很好
These taste... healthy. What's in them?
這嘗起來很...健康 放了什麼
Squash.
南瓜
Ooh. I want a cowboy.
我想要個牛仔
Sorry. That one's taken.
不好意思 名草有主了
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的? - 對
No.
不
Maybe. I don't know. It looks like we're going to be just friends.
我也不知道 似乎我們只能成為朋友了
But he hasn't met Hannah yet.
可他還沒有見過漢娜本人
Come on.
來吧
Hey, look! It's Hannah Montana!
看啊 是孟漢娜!
Oh, hi. Sorry, I... I didn't see you.
哦 對不起 我沒看見你
I'm Travis. Thanks for coming.
我叫特拉維斯 很高興你能來
Yeah, happy to help. This is Lilly. She's my assistant.
我很樂意幫忙 她是麗莉 我的手下
Executive assistant.
執行助理
Welcome to Crowley Corners.
歡迎來到克勞雷
It sure would be nice to have someone to... show us around.
如果有人...帶我們四處逛逛 就太好了
- Real smooth. - What?
- 你還真自然 - 什麼
Look, I really don't think I'm your guy. But nice to meet you.
我真的不是你們要找的人 但是 很高興見到你
No, go. Go!
不行 去 去
So... putting up a satellite dish.
在 安裝衛星天線嗎
It's a birdbath.
是給鳥玩耍的水盤
I knew that.
我聽說過
Lilly, could you go find the owner of this fine house
麗莉 能不能去找這棟美麗房子 的主人
and run them through my dietary needs?
核對我今天的菜單
Go. Assist.
去 手下
OK.
遵命
So, you and Miley are pretty close, huh?
你和麥莉很要好 是吧
You have no idea.
你無法想像
You don't have to answer if you think this is too personal,
如果很私人的話 可以不回答
but you think she'd go out with me if I asked?
但如果我約她出去 她會同意嗎
You want to go out with Miley?
你想約麥莉出去
No, you'd be a real prize. Don't get me wrong, but...
不 你的確很有魅力 不要誤會 但是
But Miley...
但是麥莉她
I can't help but smile when I'm around her.
只要她在一旁 我臉上總能掛著笑容
I think about her all the time. And I...
整天腦子裡想的都是她
You should go ask her out.
你應該去約她
- Really? - Mm-hm.
- 真的?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm going to do that right now.
對啊 我應該現在就去
No, no. No. Excuse me.
不 不 聽我說
You can't go in there. She's not home. Miley! She's not home.
你不能進去 她不在家 麥莉她出去了
She said something about going to the barn and brushing Blue Jeans.
說什麼去馬廄給藍牛仔刷毛
You should go ask her there. Go, go, go! Go. Goodbye.
你應該去那找他 去 去 去 拜拜
Go!
去
- Slow down, hot stuff. - Got to go. Got to go. Got to go.
- 慢點 急性子 - 快點 快點 快點
Miley?
麥莉?
Miley! Miley, are you...?
麥莉 麥莉 你在...
Hey, slacker.
嘿 逃兵
Uh, hey.
嘿
I was just talking to your friend, Hannah.
我剛剛跟你好朋友漢娜聊過
Actually, we were talking about you.
事實上 我們在聊你
Oh, really. Was there something you wanted to say
是嗎 你有什麼要說的嗎
or ask me or talk to me about?
問我 或告訴我什麼
Well, I know you're going home soon.
我知道你要回去了
Yeah, I am. That's right, Travis, keep going.
對 是的 特拉維斯 繼續
I was wondering if maybe you would like to go to dinner with me this evening.
我想今晚我們一起吃個飯?
OK. Sure.
可以
I don't think I have any other plans, so sounds good.
我沒有別的安排 聽上去不錯
- Cool. - Cool.
- 說定了 - 說定了
Cool.
說定了
Now you're talking. Oh, that is the one.
你現在在說 就這件
Yeah, it would be, but she's not going.
這件不錯 但她又不去
What do you mean I can't go?
我為什麼不能去
You're the one that promised Lorelai that Hannah
是你答應羅莉萊 漢娜是
would be the guest of honor at the mayor's lobster hoo-hah tonight.
今晚市長的龍蝦大宴的貴賓
- Actually, Lilly did. - Actually, Hannah did.
- 事實上 麗莉說的 - 事實上 漢娜說的
But I promised Travis.
但我答應了特拉維斯
You know what? Then I'll just leave it up to you.
你知道嗎 這爛攤子你去收拾
You do whatever you think is right.
什麼是對的自己看著辦吧
But...
但...
It's Hannah Montana!
孟漢娜
Can I have your autograph, Hannah Montana?
能給我簽個名嗎 孟漢娜
Smile.
笑一個
- Yeah! - Perfect.
完美
Where's Miley? She should be here by now.
麥莉人呢 她應該在這的
Hon, she's got East Coast-West Nile disease.
她得了東海岸西尼羅河病
- That sucker's traveling. - Yeah.
- 那個蚊蟲傳染病? - 對
If everybody could please take their seats.
各位請就坐
- Yes, be seated, everybody. - Find their place card there.
- 坐下來 大家 - 請找到自己的座位牌
And let me just say that, honestly,
請允許我衷心地感謝
to have someone of your talents,
在座各位能賞臉蒞臨
well, Miss Montana, Hannah, if you will,
孟小姐 不介意的話 漢娜
your offer of a concert tomorrow to save Crowley Meadows from such a sad fate,
你明天舉辦演唱會 以此拯救 克勞雷牧場於危難之中
well, our humble little corner of the world can't thank you enough.
我們這無名小鎮實在無以為報
And if there's ever anything that myself
如果本人或這裡的每一個人
or the good people of Crowley Corners can do for you,
能夠幫到你的話
anything you need, all you have to do is...
只要你有需要
Where did she go?
她在哪裡?
Need. I just need to check on my fans.
有 我需要慰問我的粉絲
Hannah, Hannah...
漢娜 漢娜
See? But what I really need is I need to go to the bathroom.
聽! 現在我最需要的是上趟廁所
I need to go. Lilly, come with me. Right now!
真的很急 麗莉 陪我
Makeup, clothes, it's all in there. Go.
化妝盒 衣服 都在裡面了
- I'll be right back. Cover for me. - OK.
- 我很快回來 幫我掩護
Hey.
嘿
- Sorry I'm late. - You're not late. I was early.
- 抱歉來晚了 - 是我來早了
- I got you these. - Thank you.
- 送給你 - 謝謝
You do know you only have one earring?
你只戴了一個耳環
Trendy L.A. Thing.
洛杉磯流行
- I guess you're going back there soon? - Mm-hm. Yeah.
- 我想你沒幾天就要走了 - 的確
- I'm going to go ahead and jump. - Please jump.
- 那我直接跳到重點了 - 請你快進
- Well, Miley... - Uh-huh.
麥莉
Before you leave...
你走之前
...I just...
...我想...
I really want you to know how I feel about you.
我真的想告訴你我對你的感覺
Is everything all right?
有什麼事嗎
I really should take this. I'm sorry, it will just be a second. I swear.
這個電話我必須接 一會就回來
I'll probably get better reception in the back.
店後面的信號好一些
I got two bars. Three bars.
兩格信號! 三格了!
Four bars!
四格!
Hannah. Hannah. Hannah. Hannah.
漢娜 漢娜 漢娜 漢娜
Now that our guest of honor has returned, dig in!
我們的貴賓回來了 開動
That's a heck of a crawdaddy, isn't it?
這龍蝦吃紅牛長大的啊
So, Hannah, you must have a lot of wonderful stories to tell.
漢娜 你肯定有精彩故事給我們分享
Not really.
其實沒有
I mean there are just so many.
...沒有一兩天是說不完的
But I don't want this evening to be all about me.
我可不想成為今晚的重點
I mean, everybody's stories are important, right, Jackson?
我是說 每個人都有故事 是吧 傑克森
- Huh? - You just started college.
- 什麼? - 你剛剛上大學
- Tell us about your classes. - Yeah, my classes. Uh...
- 說說你的同學吧 - 我的同學 額
I really like...
我很喜歡...
I think my favorite part is...
我最喜歡的部分是...
Dad, that your little boy is growing up into a man.
老爸 你的臭小子已經變成真男人了
Oh!
哦
Oops, dropped my napkin.
糟糕 餐巾掉了
Harlow!
哈羅
- Harlow! - Ow!
- 哈羅
- What are you doing? - Looking for a ferret.
- 你在幹什麼 - 找一支雪貂
- What are you doing? - Trying to have my first
- 你在幹什麼 - 試圖開啟我的第一次
mature relationship. Now get back up there.
成熟的情感大門 現在你給我上去
Found it.
找到了
- I'm having the lobster. - It's not on the menu.
- 我要龍蝦 - 菜單上沒有
Right.
是嗎
Sorry. It's been a weird couple of days, but...
這幾天太混亂了 對不起
Yeah.
是的
And I think I know some of the things you want to tell me.
我想我能猜到幾分你要說的話
Yeah?
是嗎
There are so many things I want to tell you, too, and...
我也有話要對你說
That's just going to have to wait.
但好像時機尚未成熟
I need to go double-check on my lobsters.
我要回去看看我的龍蝦
- Club soda will take that out. - Sit! That's enough.
- 我去拿蘇打水 - 坐下 夠了
No one is getting up from this table. No one.
沒人離開這張桌子 沒人
Dessert, anyone?
有人要甜點嗎
I'm sure you've all heard of baked Alaska.
你們肯定聽過火山冰激凌
We give you Tennessee flambe.
請看田納西火焰冰山
Mr. Mayor, I assume that you'd like to say a few final words?
市長先生 請您致結束語
Oh, yes, yes.
哦 對的
Not many people know that the Tennessee flambe was actually invented by...
鮮少有人知道 田納西火焰冰山的發明者
Come here.
過來
- Mr. Mayor! - I got you now.
- 市長 - 我抓到你了
Harlow!
哈羅
We got a fire!
起火了
Dang flam it!
真見鬼
This has all gone very well. Don't you think?
一切都在掌握之中 你覺得呢
Sorry, excuse me. Excuse me.
對不起 借過
Travis, please let me explain.
特拉維斯 聽我解釋
Explain what?
解釋什麼
That you've been making fun of me?
說你在耍我玩
Laughing at me? Lying to me this whole time?
嘲笑我 一直都在騙我?
I was honest with you. I told you how I felt.
我坦誠以對 告訴你我的感覺
- And I feel the same way. - No, you don't.
- 我對你也一樣 - 不 你不是的
Because I would have never treated you like that.
我早知道的話 不會那樣對待你了
You know what, Miley... Hannah, whoever you are?
你知道嗎 麥莉 漢娜 不管你是哪個
We're done.
我們完了
Travis!
特拉維斯
Travis, please.
特拉維斯 求你了
- Did you see? - Yeah, I saw.
- 看到了? - 我看到了
Robby Ray, is that you down there? Uh...
羅比雷 是你在下面嗎
Not now, Lorelai. I've got some family stuff going on.
現在不行 羅莉萊 我有一些家庭私事
I'm sorry. It's just this whole evening was a disaster.
對不起 這整件事太糟糕了
I just organized the whole thing, and then that girl comes in and ruins it.
我一手準備的全被那女孩 進進出出的搞砸了
I don't care if she is here for a big concert.
我可不關心她辦什麼演唱會
She's got a complicated life. I know it's hard to understand, but...
她生活已經夠複雜了 我知道很難接受
What's going on, Robby Ray?
出什麼事了 羅比
I really don't have any time for secrets and lies.
我真的沒時間忍受謊言和秘密了
I don't know if I could be happy with somebody comfortable living in them.
我不知道能不能和一個 樂在其中的人繼續下去
I know. You shouldn't have to be.
我明白 你不需要的
I should have told you the truth.
我早就應該告訴你真相
The truth is that...
真相是...
...I just don't have any place in my life for a relationship right now.
我現在沒有心情開始一段新感情
There's no room. Miley and me, we've got to sort through some things.
我和麥莉 容不下其他人 我們必須去解決這一切
And she needs me. And I kind of need to be there for her.
她需要我 我需要在她的身邊
I'm sorry.
對不起
Well, me too then.
我也一樣
Me too.
抱歉
Hannah. Hannah. Hannah. Hannah.
漢娜 漢娜 漢娜
Hey, caterpillar.
嘿 毛毛蟲
Thanks.
謝了
No problem.
不用謝
- Are you mad? - No, I'm not mad. You?
- 你生氣嗎 - 我不生氣 你?
No.
不
- How's the song coming? - I don't know. I'm not sure yet.
- 歌創作得怎麼樣 - 不知道 還沒譜呢
What's it about?
關於什麼的
You.
你
Me.
我
Us.
我們
Can I hear it?
能聽聽嗎
Miley Cyrus & Billy Ray Cyrus - Butterfly Fly Away
麥莉父女合唱 - 蝶兒飛
# You tucked me in, turned out the light
* 你把我塞進被窩 幫我關掉檯燈 *
# Kept me safe and sound at night
* 在黑夜裡讓我安然入睡 *
# Little girls depend on things like that
* 小女孩期望的不過如此 *
# Brushed my teeth and combed my hair
* 幫我刷牙 替我穿衣 *
# Had to drive me everywhere
* 載著我前往夢想的地方 *
# You were always there when I looked back
* 驀然回首 你總在原地 *
# You had to do it all alone
* 你總是獨自一人默默付出 *
# Make a living, make a home
* 為我掙錢生活 為我搭建家園 *
# It must have been as hard as it could be
* 這樣的日子肯定艱難無比 *
# And when I couldn't sleep at night
* 當我晚上無法進入夢鄉 *
# Scared things wouldn't turn out right
* 懼怕外面的狂風巨浪 *
# You would hold my hand and sing to me
* 你會抱我在懷在耳邊哼著 *
Sing with me on this part, Daddy.
和我一起唱 爸爸
# Caterpillar in the tree
* 樹枝上的毛毛蟲 *
# How you wonder who you'll be
* 可曾想過你是誰 *
# Can't go far, but you can always dream
* 不能瀟灑走四方 但是夢想無限大 *
# Wish you may and wish you might
* 送你希望 送你夢 *
# Don't you worry, hold on tight
* 不要失望 和放棄 *
# I promise you there will come a day
* 醜小鴨也有春天 *
# Butterfly, fly away
* 蝶兒飛 蝶兒飛 *
# You got your wings, now you can't stay
* 你有了雙翅可以翱翔 *
# Take those dreams and make them all come true
* 夢想未來就在前方 *
# Butterfly, butterfly, butterfly
* 蝶兒飛 蝶兒飛 蝶兒飛 *
# Butterfly, fly away #
* 蝶兒飛 蝶兒飛 *
- Miley! - Yes! What?
- 麥莉 - 在 什麼
Miley!
麥莉
- Are you OK? - Don't you know better
- 沒事吧 - 你除了對個在屋頂睡覺的人
than to yell at someone asleep on top of a chicken coop?
大叫以外 就沒有其它辦法打招呼?
I do now.
現在知道了
Did you do this? Were you out here all night?
你幹的? 通宵在這裡?
Just a little hard work. That's all.
是有點費事
Life's a climb.
生活就像攀登
Is it time?
到時候了?
Yeah, it's time.
到時候了
Let's go.
走吧
Hey!
嘿
We received a one-thousand-dollar contribution
我們收到了1000美元的捐款
- from an anonymous benefactor! - We're getting there.
- 來自拒絕透露姓名好心人士 - 正逼近目標呢
Oh, hey.
哦 嘿
Isn't it awesome? This is terrific! See you at the concert.
是不是很棒啊 沒話說 演唱會見
- Coming through. Coming through. - Stay back!
- 借過 借過 - 退後
I'm not the agent, I'm not the manager, I'm the grandma.
不是經紀人 不是經理 我是奶奶
- I'm the real deal. - She's OK.
- 如假包換的 - 讓她進去
Have a good day, ma'am.
祝您愉快 女士
Whew, honey. I had no idea.
甜心 我真沒想到
No wonder they hide you away in this camper thingie.
難怪他們要把你關在這野營車裡
Is it always this crazy?
每次都這麼瘋狂?
Always.
無一例外
Well, I know the getting here was hard, but what you're doing is a good thing.
我知道你走到這一步不容易 但你多做的意義非凡
You should be proud of that.
你應該引以為豪
I know I am.
我為你驕傲
This was my mom's?
這是媽媽的?
She'd be proud of you too.
她也會為你驕傲的
Thanks.
謝謝
Um, I'm just gonna put it in here so I can...
我要把它放在這
So I can have it in my pocket with my show and everything.
這樣表演的時候 它就在口袋裡
That's good, close to you.
很好 很貼心
Thank you. I love you.
謝謝 奶奶 我愛你
I love you, darling.
我也愛你 寶貝
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
漢娜 漢娜 漢娜
Hannah Montana - Rock Star
孟漢娜 - 搖滾明星
Sometimes I walk a little faster
* 有時候在學校的走廊 *
In the school hallway
* 我故意加快腳步 *
Just to get next to you
* 就想走到你身旁 *
Some days I spend a little extra
* 有時後起床醒來 *
Time in the morning
* 特地精心打扮 *
Dress to impress you
* 就為了讓你留下印象 *
Guess you don't notice
* 或許你沒注意到 *
Guess you don't need this
* 或許你根本不在意 *
Sad you're not seein' what you're missin'
* 真可惜 我就是你遺失的美好 *
On the outside shyin' away
* 在外面害羞的跑走 *
On the inside dyin' to say
* 在裡面好想跟你說 *
I'm unusual
* 我可不平凡 *
Not so typical
* 我可不一般 *
Way too smart to be waiting around
* 我怎麼會傻傻等著你 *
Tai chi practices
* 平常沒事練太極 *
Snowboard champion
* 雪地滑板我最行 *
I could fix the flat on your car
* 板金工夫難不倒 *
I might even be a rock star
* 我還能是搖滾明星 *
I can't do this.
我不行
Sorry.
對不起
I've loved being Hannah, but I just don't think I can do it anymore.
我過去喜歡當漢娜 但現在沒有辦法
At least not here, not with you guys.
起碼這裡不行 在你們面前
See, this is... this is home.
因為 這是 這是我的家
This is where I'm from. This is family.
生我養我的地方
And there's only so many sacrifices you can ask a family to make.
唯一可以任性撒嬌 有家人包容的地方
The last time I stood on this stage I was six.
我上一次站在這裡是6歲
I was...
當時...
I was just Miley.
...我只是麥莉
And I still am.
現在我仍然是
It's me.
這就是我
I've hurt a lot of people, but... I didn't mean to.
我傷害了很多人 但不是真心的
And... if it's not too late...
如果為時不晚的話
...I sure would like a second chance.
我希望你們給我第二次機會
I know you all came to hear Hannah, but...
我知道你們是來聽漢娜唱歌的
...if you don't mind, I've written y'all a song.
不介意的話 我為你們寫了首歌
It's kind of personal.
是關於我自己的
It's about what I've learned over the last couple weeks.
關於幾個星期裡我學到的
Life's a climb.
生活就像攀登
But the view is great.
沿途風景獨美
Miley Cyrus - The Climb
麥莉希拉 - 攀登
I can almost see it
* 我眼前依稀浮現 *
That dream I'm dreamin' but
* 我夢見的那個夢境 *
There's a voice inside my head saying
* 腦海裡卻有一個聲音 *
you'll never reach it
* 說我永遠也不會成功 *
Every step I'm taking
* 我所走過的每一步 *
Every move I make feels
* 我做過的每一件事 *
Lost with no direction
* 都迷失了方向 *
My faith is shakin
* 我的信念開始動搖 *
But I, I gotta keep tryin
* 但我 我還是要繼續尋求 *
Gotta keep my head held high
* 要勇敢抬頭 大步向前走 *
There's always gonna be another mountain
* 要爬的山嶽總是爬不完 *
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
* 我總會要設法移開 *
Always gonna be an uphill battle
* 永遠都充滿了挑戰 *
Sometimes I'm gonna have to lose
* 有時候還是會被擊倒 *
Ain't about how fast I get there
* 不關乎多快才能到達 *
Ain't about what's waitin on the other side
* 也不管將來會怎樣 *
It's the climb
* 這就是攀登 *
The struggles I'm facing
* 我所要面對的難關 *
The chances I'm taking
* 我所抓住的每個機遇 *
Sometimes might knock me down but
* 雖然有時後會被擊倒 *
No I'm not breaking
* 但我絕對不認輸 *
I may not know it
* 我或許不懂 不瞭解 *
But these are the moments that
* 但這一些的點點滴滴 *
I'm gonna remember most, yeah
* 我永遠不會忘記 *
Just gotta keep going
* 只管繼續前進 *
And I, I gotta be strong
* 而我 我得要堅強 *
Just keep pushing on 'cause
* 只管努力向前行 因為 *
There's always gonna be another mountain
* 要爬的山嶽總是爬不完 *
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
* 我總會要設法移開 *
Always gonna be an uphill battle
* 永遠都充滿了挑戰 *
Sometimes I'm gonna have to lose
* 有時候還是會被擊倒 *
Ain't about how fast I get there
* 不關乎多快才能到達 *
Ain't about what's waitin on the other side
* 也不管將來會怎樣 *
It's the climb
* 這就是攀登 *
There's always gonna be another mountain
* 要爬的山嶽總是爬不完 *
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
* 我總會要設法移開 *
Always gonna be an uphill battle
* 永遠都充滿了挑戰 *
Sometimes I'm gonna have to lose
* 有時候還是會被擊倒 *
Ain't about how fast I get there
* 不關乎多快才能到達 *
Ain't about what's waitin on the other side
* 也不管將來會怎樣 *
It's the climb
* 這就是攀登 *
Keep on moving
* 繼續向前行 *
Keep climbing
* 繼續攀登 *
Keep the faith
* 保持信念 *
It's all about
* 這就是 *
It's all about the climb
* 這就是攀登 *
Keep the faith
* 保持信念 *
Thanks for letting me live my Hannah.
謝謝給我機會當我的漢娜
Bye.
再見
Please.
求你了
Please be Hannah. We'll keep your secret.
繼續當漢娜 我們會為你保守秘密的
I'm sorry, I can't. It's too late.
對不起 我不行 太晚了
Sure, you can!
你當然可以
Put the wig back on. You'll never have a normal life if you don't!
戴上假髮 你已經不能變回普通的女孩
Hannah's a part of you! Don't let her go!
漢娜是你的一部分 不要讓她走
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
漢娜 漢娜 漢娜
No, please.
不 別
- Somebody, stop him! - Call security!
- 來人攔住他 - 叫保安
Watch it! One more step and I hit "send. "
小心點 再過來 我就按"發送"
- Don't do it. - Sorry, nothing on Earth'll
- 別這樣 - 抱歉 世界上這會沒人能
- stop me from... - Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
- 阻止我 - 爸爸 爸爸 爸爸
Phoebe, Clarissa, what are you doing?
菲比 克拉麗莎 你們跑來幹嘛
This nice lady sorted it all out. Two free tickets.
這位女士都安排好了 機票免費
Upper class. It was brilliant!
頭等艙 酷斃了
I thought the girls'd appreciate a couple of free tickets.
我想她們需要兩張機票
We too late? She going to sing again?
我們晚了嗎 她還會唱一首嗎
I can't believe that I'm only one degree away...
真不相信 我只差一步之遙 和
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
漢娜 漢娜 漢娜
- My gosh! It's Hannah Montana! - It's really her!
- 天哪 是孟漢娜 - 真的是她
- You're right there! I'm here! - I can't believe it!
- 我就在你面前 是我 - 打死我也不信
I really love you. We're your biggest fans ever, really.
我愛死你了 我們是你的終極粉絲
You're not going to destroy their dreams, are you?
你不會讓女兒夢想破滅吧
That's what Hannah's all about.
漢娜的命運就在你手上
- Is that your story? - I must be dreaming! Pinch me!
- 這就是你的素材? - 我在做夢吧 捏我一下
No, that's not my story.
不 不是我的素材
- Oh, my gosh! - Girls!
- 天哪 - 孩子們
- Get this down, Lucinda. - Fire away, Ozzie.
給我聽好了 露辛達
Bon Chic magazine
雜誌的頭是把快樂建立在
is run by a wretched, soulless succubus who preys on the misfortune of others,
別人痛苦上的 醜陋冷血黑山老妖
and I'm not going to put up with it any longer!
給你說我受夠了
Ozzie! Ozzie! Come...
奧齊 奧齊
Think I just quit.
我想我辭職了
Come on. Let's go out front. I think Hannah's got more songs in her.
我們回去前台 漢娜還有歌沒唱完
Thanks, partner.
謝謝 兄弟
- Everybody, stay where you are. - Miley!
- 大家請在原地 別亂動 - 麥莉
We got lots more music for you.
我們還有更多的歌送給你們
Remember that crush I had on you, and I said I was over it?
記得我說過喜歡你 還說我結束了?
Yeah.
記得
Please jump.
請你快進
So not over it.
可還沒有結束
Right on!
開場了
You wake up, it's raining and it's monday
* 一早醒來 是個下雨的星期一 *
Looks like one of those rough days
* 看來又是一個倒楣日 *
Time's up, you're late again, so get out the door
* 時間到 你又遲到了 快出門吧 *
Sometimes you feel like running
* 有時候感覺像在賽跑 *
Find a whole new life and jump in
* 找個新生活 一頭栽進 *
Let go, get up and hit the dance floor
* 來吧 趕快稱霸舞台 *
Cause when I'm feeling down and I am all alone
* 因為當我不開心 又孤單的時候 *
I've always got a place where I can go
* 總有個地方歡迎我 *
Cause I know
* 因我知道 *
You can change your hair and you can change your clothes
* 你可以換髮型 可以換衣服 *
You can change your mind, that's just the way it goes
* 你可以改變想法 就是這樣 *
You can say goodbye, you can say hello
* 你可以說再見 可以說你好 *
But you'll always find your way back home
* 但你永遠可以找到回家的路 *
You can change your style Yeah your can change your jeans
* 你可以改變造型 可以換條牛仔褲 *
You can learn to fly and you can chase your dreams
* 你可以學習飛翔 可以追尋夢想 *
You can laugh and cry but everybody knows
* 你可以哭 可以笑 但大家都知道 *
You'll always find your way back home
* 你永遠可以找到回家的路 *
Where they know exactly who you are
* 家人都知道你是誰 *
Back home where the real you is the superstar
* 雖然是個大明星 但只要回家 *
Back home, you know it's never too far away
* 只要回家 你就知道 家離你不遠 *
You can change your hair and you can change your clothes
* 你可以換髮型 可以換衣服 *
You can change your mind, that's just the way it goes
* 你可以改變想法 就是這樣 *
You can say goodbye, you can say hello
* 你可以說再見 可以說你好 *
But you'll always find your way back
* 但你永遠可以找到回家的路 *
You can change your hair and you can change your clothes
* 你可以換髮型 可以換衣服 *
You can change your mind, that's just the way it goes
* 你可以改變想法 就是這樣 *
You can say goodbye, you can say hello
* 你可以說再見 可以說你好 *
But you'll always find your way back home
* 但你永遠可以找到回家的路 *
You can change your style Yeah your can change your jeans
* 你可以改變造型 可以換條牛仔褲 *
You can learn to fly and you can chase your dreams
* 你可以學習飛翔 可以追尋夢想 *
You can laugh and cry but everybody knows
* 你可以哭 可以笑 但大家都知道 *
You'll always find your way back home
* 你永遠可以找到回家的路 *
Miley Cyrus - Hoedown Throwdown
繼續觀賞  麥莉希拉 - 來跳舞吧
Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
* 左提 右夾 手指點點 鄉村風格加嘻哈 *
Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
* 老鷹張翅放胸前 左右來回晃一晃 *
Jump to the left, stick it, glide
* 跳到左邊 穩住 滑 *
Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
* 地上劃出一個Z 斜線腳尖不離地 *
When the drum hits, hands on your hips
* 當鼓聲響起 雙手放腰間 *
One-footed 180 twist and then a zigzag, step, slide
* 單腳轉過180° Z字步 跨 滑 *
Lean it left, clap three times
* 左甩頭 拍三下 *
Shake it out head to toe, throw it all together, that's how we roll
* 從頭到腳我最搖擺 加在一起 就是這樣 *
And cut it!
就這樣 收工!